Have you heard the real story about this
crazy math problem? This is one of the
hardest math problems of all time.
There's a million-dollar prize for
solving it, and someone just did it.
But, there's big drama about who
deserves credit. So, there's this set of
equations that we use all the time for
everything from airplanes to blood flow
to your weather app to model how fluids
move because doing this is really hard.
And they basically use a math shortcut
that treats liquid like one continuous
soup as opposed to a bunch of little
molecules, which it really is. But, the
problem is we don't actually know if
these equations always work or if
there's some set of conditions where the
math blows up. And we rely on it so much
that trying to blow it up has become one
of the seven famous millennium prize
[music] problems. To solve the problem,
you have to prove either one, the math
never blows up, or two, the math does
blow up in this specific set of
circumstances. People have been trying
to solve this problem for a hundred
years, but recently two scientists used
a bunch of different AI tools and seem
to be getting really close to proving
that second option. But, then OpenAI
heard about this and threw a bunch more
resources at this problem. And just 88
[music] hours later, as I understand it,
they solved it. Exactly how is also
controversial, but the big drama is it's
possible those two scientists
unknowingly taught OpenAI tools how to
solve the problem by using them. OpenAI
says, "Maybe." But, what really matters
here is both groups were using new
technology to solve a problem we never
solved before. For more like this,
subscribe.